{"posts":[{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"c programming questions","salience":0.37996143102645874},{"name":"functions","salience":0.3382582664489746},{"name":"helper","salience":0.1075744777917862},{"name":"answers","salience":0.10018181800842285},{"name":"libraries","salience":0.0370120108127594},{"name":"reason","salience":0.0370120108127594}],"question":" For the C programming questions, can we implement our own \"helper\" functions and then call them in our answers? Can we also include any extra libraries if for whatever reason we decide to? ","answers":[" Yes and yes. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"part","salience":0.26639124751091003},{"name":"question","salience":0.09527186304330826},{"name":"bigarray","salience":0.07047706097364426},{"name":"page","salience":0.06335536390542984},{"name":"answer","salience":0.04917335882782936},{"name":"code","salience":0.03995761647820473},{"name":"pages","salience":0.024325840175151825},{"name":"pages","salience":0.024205820634961128},{"name":"sum","salience":0.02370002306997776},{"name":"code","salience":0.02331695705652237},{"name":"set","salience":0.019424403086304665},{"name":"process","salience":0.019424403086304665},{"name":"working set","salience":0.019424403086304665},{"name":"array","salience":0.01781495101749897},{"name":"pages","salience":0.016515403985977173},{"name":"pages","salience":0.016314534470438957},{"name":"code","salience":0.01582837663590908},{"name":"sum","salience":0.015641281381249428},{"name":"code","salience":0.015635810792446136},{"name":"data","salience":0.014966811053454876},{"name":"process","salience":0.013129852712154388},{"name":"int","salience":0.012122859247028828},{"name":"page","salience":0.011405093595385551},{"name":"pages","salience":0.011128785088658333},{"name":"code","salience":0.0109297139570117},{"name":"values","salience":0.010590331628918648},{"name":"window","salience":0.010526977479457855},{"name":"all","salience":0.008340819738805294},{"name":"process","salience":0.007699089124798775},{"name":"set","salience":0.007681870833039284},{"name":"code","salience":0.007639537565410137},{"name":"variables","salience":0.007328053005039692},{"name":"registers","salience":0.007328053005039692},{"name":"system","salience":0.005131341516971588},{"name":"piece","salience":0.005119853653013706},{"name":"sum","salience":0.0039550201036036015},{"name":"questions","salience":0.0036609694361686707},{"name":"assumptions","salience":0.003215709701180458},{"name":"i++","salience":0.0019005427602678537}],"question":" I'm confused abut the part a of this tutorial question. Why the answer is 2 instead of 99 (1 page for the code and 98 pages for the big array)? The working set of a process could be defined as the set of pages being referenced by the process over a small window of time. This would naturally include the pages containing the code being executed, and the pages holding the data being accessed by this code. Consider the following code which computes the sum of all values in a very large array: int bigArray[100000];...int sum = 0;for (int i = 0; i &lt; 100000; i++) sum += bigArray[i]; Answer the questions below under the assumptions that: pages are 4KB; all of the above code fits in a single page; the sum and i variables are implemented in registers; there is just one process running in the system. How large is the working set of this piece of code? ","answers":[" From my understanding, you just need 2 because when the OS is managing each process, you only ever need to see the code you're looking at (1 page) and then 1 other page for the array part you're looking at. The whole thing with the working set model is that you don't or should not load all pages up because that is unnecessary since you only will look at each page in terms of the array section maybe once and if they are needed to be looked at again, then they will be loaded up again. Otherwise the remaining total pages in the 'whole system' could/would be allocated to other segments for other processes. ",[" Correct. The two pages are the page containing the code for the for loop, plus the page containing the section of the array that you're currently looking at. ",[" When talking about the valgrind memory leak is that detected from the physical memory or the virtual memory ? ",[" Process memory "]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"check q1","salience":0.3410959541797638},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.15595084428787231},{"name":"prac exam","salience":0.10679019242525101},{"name":"code","salience":0.1048445850610733},{"name":"output","salience":0.07544492930173874},{"name":"input","salience":0.0664420798420906},{"name":"tests","salience":0.05029929056763649},{"name":"output","salience":0.049417443573474884},{"name":"trick","salience":0.02713020332157612},{"name":"running check","salience":0.02258448861539364}],"question":" When I use check q1 on the sample exams (5 released for the prac exam), they are all showing failed tests, although I am sure the code is correct, as they produce correct output if I manually insert input and crosscheck with output. Is there a trick to running check? ","answers":[" Are you sure it's not just the \"Loading:\" message at the start of the output? Alternatively, trailing spaces or non-printing characters. Are you cross-checking using your eyes (easily deceived) or using diff ? "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"way","salience":0.6049523949623108},{"name":"mips","salience":0.22569355368614197},{"name":"asciiz array","salience":0.16935403645038605}],"question":" What is the proper way to access asciiz array in MIPS? ","answers":[" It's just an array of bytes, terminated by a 0 byte. If you want one of the bytes, try lb . "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"fragment","salience":0.37913239002227783},{"name":"questions","salience":0.2026287168264389},{"name":"program","salience":0.16459378600120544},{"name":"code","salience":0.07441139966249466},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.053257934749126434},{"name":"code","salience":0.017618047073483467},{"name":"program","salience":0.011205715127289295},{"name":"code fragment","salience":0.010634019039571285},{"name":"bracket","salience":0.009779511950910091},{"name":"code","salience":0.00952967256307602},{"name":"question","salience":0.00832707155495882},{"name":"aim","salience":0.007946345955133438},{"name":"programming logic","salience":0.007077294401824474},{"name":"case","salience":0.006776738446205854},{"name":"order","salience":0.006751306354999542},{"name":"executable","salience":0.006669084075838327},{"name":"question","salience":0.004778868518769741},{"name":"syntax errors","salience":0.004677909426391125},{"name":"semi-colon","salience":0.004677909426391125},{"name":"programming logic","salience":0.003729329677298665},{"name":"code fragment","salience":0.0030368792358785868},{"name":"question","salience":0.0027600564062595367}],"question":" Looking through the sample exams there are a few questions that ask us to write a code 'fragment'. The question doesn't say \"write a full program\" which would involve writing all required code in order to have a working executable. This implies to me we don't have to compile the code 'fragment' we submit as it won't be a complete program. That being the case, is the code fragment expected to be syntactically perfect or is the aim of the question to demonstrate the programming logic required to achieve what the question asks? Without compiling the code fragment there is a high likelihood there will be atleast one or two small syntax errors i.e. missing bracket or semi-colon so I would like to understand is this particularly important or should we just be focusing on the programming logic in what we submit? ","answers":[" If it's not a prac question, then I won't be expecting syntactic perfection. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"terminator","salience":0.4011894166469574},{"name":"data section","salience":0.1459122598171234},{"name":"mips code","salience":0.1459122598171234},{"name":"nterm: .byte '\\0","salience":0.11674834042787552},{"name":"syntax","salience":0.04530927538871765},{"name":"advice","salience":0.04508686065673828},{"name":"number","salience":0.03396763280034065},{"name":"terminator","salience":0.02712075598537922},{"name":"thanks","salience":0.023778745904564857},{"name":"char","salience":0.014974452555179596}],"question":" How can we define the null terminator in the .data section of our MIPS code? .data NTERM: .byte '\\0' The above throws an error - invalid syntax. Please advice. Are we explicitly supposed to check against char '0' or the number 0 when looking for the null terminator? Thanks! ","answers":[" Just use the number 0, i.e. NTERM: .byte 0 ",[" Thanks Jas! "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"answer","salience":0.3198208510875702},{"name":"size","salience":0.21813073754310608},{"name":"practice exam","salience":0.06460162997245789},{"name":"size","salience":0.06208522617816925},{"name":"2017s2","salience":0.056736499071121216},{"name":"component","salience":0.042334042489528656},{"name":"components","salience":0.03887799009680748},{"name":"piece","salience":0.0336625911295414},{"name":"components","salience":0.02937169373035431},{"name":"memory","salience":0.02907785214483738},{"name":"all","salience":0.024972546845674515},{"name":"padding","salience":0.021951669827103615},{"name":"compiler","salience":0.020604129880666733},{"name":"fields","salience":0.01538856141269207},{"name":"answers","salience":0.012730793096125126},{"name":"struct","salience":0.009653173387050629}],"question":" Hi, I'm not too sure why the answer to Q3) C) i) on the 2017S2 practice exam is 8bytes? your answers say \"# it's the size of the largest component, # all components share the same piece of memory\" I thought the size of a struct is the size of all of its components added together (+ padding if the compiler doesnt re-arrange the fields)? ","answers":[" It's not a struct . It's a union . Big difference. ",[" / "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"curious","salience":0.3378407657146454},{"name":"17s2","salience":0.21465913951396942},{"name":"memory","salience":0.14462514221668243},{"name":"memory","salience":0.11356448382139206},{"name":"middle","salience":0.09987923502922058},{"name":"one","salience":0.0342494435608387},{"name":"memory","salience":0.031094346195459366},{"name":"another","salience":0.02408745512366295}],"question":" Curious about 17S2, q7, why there is a empty memory in the middle of the physical memory? Isn't physical memory filled up one after another? ","answers":[" The contents of physical memory evolves as processes come and go. Process pages are allocated to whatever frames happen to be free at the time they're needed, so they won't necessarily be allocated to consecutive frames in memory. This physical memory might have an empty frame because some process just finished and released it. ",[" I see, thanks a lot! "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"something","salience":0.3247763514518738},{"name":"sample","salience":0.16655398905277252},{"name":"lectures","salience":0.0821506530046463},{"name":"c","salience":0.03286656737327576},{"name":"decimal","salience":0.03156811743974686},{"name":"code","salience":0.03156811743974686},{"name":"c","salience":0.030564522370696068},{"name":"c","salience":0.028857000172138214},{"name":"b","salience":0.024528158828616142},{"name":"scanf","salience":0.024173427373170853},{"name":"d","salience":0.023080168291926384},{"name":"d","salience":0.023080168291926384},{"name":"memory","salience":0.021355541422963142},{"name":"testing","salience":0.021249881014227867},{"name":"n","salience":0.021062560379505157},{"name":"void","salience":0.019676264375448227},{"name":"int","salience":0.019676264375448227},{"name":"stdio.h&gt","salience":0.019676264375448227},{"name":"printf","salience":0.01484515331685543},{"name":"b","salience":0.012975367717444897},{"name":"``%d %d %d","salience":0.010154111310839653},{"name":"b","salience":0.008137967437505722},{"name":"scanf","salience":0.0074233971536159515}],"question":" Why in qn4b of the sample is c set to 0? I recall in the lectures something about it stopping once it sees the decimal, and when I compiled and ran some code to test, C was set to 1 (I presume what was held in the memory beforehand). After some further testing, c isn't being changed by the scanf at all. So only when I initialise c to 0 as below, it still spits out c = 0 #include &lt;stdio.h&gt; int main(void){ int n, a, b, c; c = 0; n = scanf(\"%d %d %d\", &amp;a, &amp;b, &amp;c); printf(\"N: %d\\nA: %d\\nB: %d\\nC: %d\\n\", n, a, b, c); return 0; } ","answers":[" It read 42 and assigns that to a. It reads 64 and assigns that to b. It stops at the '.' because that character is not a valid char to find in a decimal integer. When it tries to find a value for c, it looks at the '.' and says \"Hmmm. Not an integer and gives up without changing c. ",[" Thanks - so to confirm, the solutions where it says '0' for should be a '?' instead since c is uninitialised: https://cgi.cse.unsw.edu.au/~cs1521/18s2/exams/sample/soln/q4.soln.txt ",[" In the code you posted, c is initialised to 0 ",[" But not in the actual question's code (sorry upon rereading I realised my question wasn't particularly clear) https://cgi.cse.unsw.edu.au/~cs1521/18s2/exams/sample/Q04.html ",[" In that case \"?\" or \"undefined\" or \"garbage\" would be acceptable "]]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"mistake","salience":0.41602256894111633},{"name":"practice paper","salience":0.14259381592273712},{"name":"octal","salience":0.09863916039466858},{"name":"complement binary","salience":0.09746599942445755},{"name":"technicality","salience":0.07900120317935944},{"name":"2","salience":0.058253638446331024},{"name":"wolframalpha","salience":0.054169218987226486},{"name":"answers","salience":0.030475974082946777},{"name":"question","salience":0.023378418758511543}],"question":" Is there a mistake in q6e from the practice paper - when I convert the 2's complement binary straight into octal, I get 177634 (confirmed with wolframalpha), vs the 177632 which the answers suggest. Or is there some technicality in this question which I'm overlooking? ","answers":[" No. It was wrong and I've fixed it. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"questions","salience":0.18264374136924744},{"name":"answer","salience":0.16393113136291504},{"name":"sample exam","salience":0.16393113136291504},{"name":"e. sigtstp","salience":0.09994910657405853},{"name":"process","salience":0.07373730093240738},{"name":"control-z","salience":0.06502869725227356},{"name":"process","salience":0.05027693882584572},{"name":"action","salience":0.04908132180571556},{"name":"action","salience":0.029639100655913353},{"name":"stop","salience":0.026073342189192772},{"name":"man page","salience":0.02469615638256073},{"name":"man page","salience":0.01698249951004982},{"name":"theorem questions","salience":0.015028025023639202},{"name":"e. -100_16","salience":0.014584447257220745},{"name":"program","salience":0.013048399239778519},{"name":"way","salience":0.006565812975168228},{"name":"octal","salience":0.0048028649762272835}],"question":" Hi, I have 2 questions about the answer of sample exam E. SIGTSTP - user types control-Z in controlling terminal - suspend process for this one, why the action is not stop the process? I think in the man page the default action is Stop? E. -100_16 = 0xff9c -100_8 = 0177632 -100_2 = 1111 1111 1001 1100 And for this one, I think the Octal should be 0177634? By the way, just to make sure, we are allowed to use man page and writing a program to do the theorem questions, right? Thank you! ","answers":[" Depends what you mean by stop. In this context, \"stop\"ping a process means halting execution, but leaving the process active. The process can be restarted from the point it was stopped. I'd call this \"suspended\". The man page calls it \"stopped\". Yes. 0177632 is a typo. I've changed it 0177634 And, yes, as I've said quite a few times, you have access to the Unix man pages during the exam. ",[" Okay, Thank you! "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"point *temptl","salience":0.23634102940559387},{"name":"code","salience":0.13497968018054962},{"name":"exam","salience":0.1256478726863861},{"name":"question","salience":0.12417631596326828},{"name":"temptl","salience":0.05888671427965164},{"name":"structure","salience":0.042128220200538635},{"name":"coord-&gt","salience":0.026818718761205673},{"name":"coord-&gt","salience":0.026818718761205673},{"name":"temptl-&gt","salience":0.024669155478477478},{"name":"issues","salience":0.023609066382050514},{"name":"d","salience":0.02125825546681881},{"name":"coord-&gt","salience":0.01858685165643692},{"name":"coord-&gt","salience":0.01858685165643692},{"name":"point","salience":0.017450273036956787},{"name":"error","salience":0.0167903583496809},{"name":"error messages","salience":0.014756157994270325},{"name":"type argument","salience":0.014756157994270325},{"name":"data structure","salience":0.008873246610164642},{"name":"something","salience":0.008841955102980137},{"name":"d","salience":0.00827145203948021},{"name":"understanding","salience":0.007795601151883602},{"name":"someone","salience":0.007537041325122118},{"name":"coord","salience":0.006857448257505894},{"name":"printf","salience":0.0055628577247262}],"question":" Hi, I have a question about q2 of the 17s2 exam. I'm confused as to why I'm having issues printing the Point structure. My code reads as follows: Point *tempTL while(read(in, tempTL, sizeof(Point)) !=0) { printf(\"%d, %d\\n\", tempTL-&gt;coord-&gt;x, tempTL-&gt;coord-&gt;y ); } My error messages reads q2.c:74:44: error: invalid type argument of '-&gt;' (have 'Coord') printf(\"%d, %d\\n\", tempTL-&gt;coord-&gt;x, tempTL-&gt;coord-&gt;y); From my understanding of the data structure this should be fine. Could someone please tell me if I'm missing something? ","answers":[" Whilst you've created tempTL as a pointer, tempTL.coord is not a pointer (so using -&gt; notation isn't valid to access the x and y values) so instead of tempTL-&gt;coord-&gt;x try (tempTL-&gt;coord).x and same for the y ",[" Ahhh thank you for that. "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"exe","salience":0.44221949577331543},{"name":"scripts","salience":0.31849998235702515},{"name":"advice","salience":0.14053872227668762},{"name":"thanks","salience":0.098741814494133}],"question":" How are we meant to install the exe and check scripts? Please advice. Thanks! ","answers":[" You don't need to. They're in ~cs1521/bin ... fix your PATH. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"mergesort","salience":0.26460254192352295},{"name":"function mergesort","salience":0.23762255907058716},{"name":"exam","salience":0.15886181592941284},{"name":"qsort","salience":0.059108760207891464},{"name":"answer","salience":0.04634381830692291},{"name":"cse machine","salience":0.04271339997649193},{"name":"make","salience":0.04271339997649193},{"name":"sorting function","salience":0.03658999130129814},{"name":"mergesort","salience":0.030195215716958046},{"name":"exam","salience":0.025665925815701485},{"name":"thanks","salience":0.02250673621892929},{"name":"advance","salience":0.02250673621892929},{"name":"declaration","salience":0.010569097474217415}],"question":" Hi, I would like to ask if the built-in function mergesort() can be used in exam? I found in the answer there is qsort(). I used mergesort() on 17s2 q3. However it doesn't compile on CSE machine with make, telling implicit declaration of mergesort(). So is it OK to use built-in sorting function such as mergesort in exam? Thanks in advance! ","answers":[" It's fine to use ant sorting function from the library. But, as I said elsewhere, I'd be disappointed if you couldn't produce a bubble sort yourself. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"program","salience":0.3213198184967041},{"name":"_&lt","salience":0.30825671553611755},{"name":"prac exams","salience":0.12443913519382477},{"name":"q1","salience":0.12299216538667679},{"name":"test","salience":0.12299216538667679}],"question":" Hello, i can't figure out why my program for q1 in practice Prac Exams can't pass the test even it has the same output with the expected output.&gt;_&lt; ","answers":[" As jas has stated \"The expected output contains a line (the \"Loaded\" one) which is filtered out of your output by check . Feel free to change the expected output files and remove the \"Loaded\" lines if you want the satisfaction of seeing \"Test X Passed\".\" so in the expected file there is the line \"Loaded: /home/class/lib/exceptions\". So neglecting that, it looks like you have the correct output. Could also delete that line from the expected files. ",[" THX MATE "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"answers","salience":0.5692464113235474},{"name":"q4bi 17s2","salience":0.3465813398361206},{"name":"liz","salience":0.08417220413684845}],"question":" Hello, I was wondering where the 8 came from in the answers for Q4Bi 17s2? i) 68 = 4+20+20+1+3+4+1+3+4+8 ^ Thanks, Liz. ","answers":[" The major[] field was 6 bytes. Need to round up to a multiple of 4. ",[" I am still a little confused about this. I know from the lectures that character pointers can be any number, so is this a principle of arrays, structs or something else (i.e. do we want the 68 to be a multiple of 4 or the 8 to be a multiple of 4)? If, for example, the array was of size 2 characters would it be rounded up to 4? Also, is there a name for this principle so I can do some further reading? Thanks! ",[" It's because we want the total size of the struct to be a multiple of 4. So that we can put structs one after another in memory without needing padding between them. Character arrays can be any length you want. Whether padding is needed after them depends on what kind of value is following, or on whether it's the last field in the struct. ",[" Thanks! :) "]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"questions","salience":0.4111788868904114},{"name":"directories","salience":0.1730707883834839},{"name":"q1","salience":0.14142483472824097},{"name":"files","salience":0.12014740705490112},{"name":"sample final exam","salience":0.10592179745435715},{"name":"directories","salience":0.032524995505809784},{"name":"someone","salience":0.01573130302131176}],"question":" The questions in \"Sample Final Exam\" refer to files is directories called q1, q2 etc. Can someone tell me where these directories are? ","answers":[" They don't exist. However, I think at least one of the questions was like one of the practice prac exam questions, so you can use the files for them. You could always take the solution files, remove the appropriate function, then try to recreate what it did. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"o_creat","salience":0.3016602396965027},{"name":"o_wronly","salience":0.1639978438615799},{"name":"q5 comp1521","salience":0.15275363624095917},{"name":"something","salience":0.11317770928144455},{"name":"operations","salience":0.11317770928144455},{"name":"numbers","salience":0.050558917224407196},{"name":"example","salience":0.03441162779927254},{"name":"solution","salience":0.027013203129172325},{"name":"c","salience":0.013617306016385555},{"name":"printf","salience":0.013617306016385555},{"name":"solution","salience":0.008105429820716381},{"name":"numbers","salience":0.007909072563052177}],"question":" I'm not getting something about the bitwise operations on the (I assume octal) numbers here in Q5 COMP1521 17s2 Final Exam: For example the solution for (ii) is given as \"O_WRONLY | O_CREAT or 00000101\" But when I try to replicate that in C with printf(\"O_WRONLY | O_CREAT is %o\\n\", (O_WRONLY | O_CREAT)); I get O_WRONLY | O_CREAT is 1001 How are the numbers in the solution generated? ","answers":[" How are the numbers in the solution generated? I got them off a man page, if I remember correctly. Maybe some Unix system #defines the symbolic names differently. Or maybe I copied them wrong. Either way, you should work with whatever values are given and answer relative to those. I was actually expecting symbolic answers rather than numeric. If you simply wrote 00001001 as your answer, I would assume that you'd messed up the bitwise OR and mark it wrong. If you want to write a program that gives you a different result, say how you generated this result (e.g. give your one-liner), and if it's valid, then I'd mark it as correct. Note: if I run your program on williams.cse.unsw.edu.au it gives 00000101 ",[" What do you know, the results on different systems must be different. OK that clears it up a bit I guess. I'll stick to symbolic answers if it comes up! Thanks. ",[" Though the answer given for (i) looks wrong no matter what. \"O_RDWR | O_APPEND or 00000102\" Looking at the given #defines and also the output on weill, is should definitely be 00002002. ",[" Fixed. Thanks. "]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"page table entries","salience":0.3181287348270416},{"name":"pages","salience":0.27728378772735596},{"name":"page table entries","salience":0.22495095431804657},{"name":"page","salience":0.054316092282533646},{"name":"page table entires","salience":0.04776177182793617},{"name":"thanks","salience":0.04752643033862114},{"name":"process address space","salience":0.030032237991690636}],"question":" Hi, For 2017 q7b, why is there 8 page table entries and 5 page table entries contain loaded pages? I noticed that there is an empty page in process address space, why not 7 page table entires? Thanks. ","answers":[" There are 8 page table entries for the process' address space. And there are 5 memory frames in the physical memory. Only 7 of the pages in the process' address space are currently in use. The other page might eventually have stuff put into it if e.g. enough objects are created with malloc. ",[" But why not 6 memory frames in the physical memory(including the empty one)? ",[" The number of memory frames is determined by the size of physical memory. It has no correlation with the size of any process address space. "]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"shepherd","salience":0.5317078232765198},{"name":"vlab","salience":0.1320323795080185},{"name":"questions","salience":0.1067207008600235},{"name":"home","salience":0.1067207008600235},{"name":"exam files","salience":0.04546535015106201},{"name":"files.tar","salience":0.03586684539914131},{"name":"lot","salience":0.017312001436948776},{"name":"error","salience":0.013269142247736454},{"name":"download page","salience":0.010905041359364986}],"question":" Dr. Shepherd, I am working on these questions at home using Vlab. How am I able to install the exam files (files.tar) into Vlab? If I try to access the download page in Vlab, it will just give me error. Thanks a lot! ","answers":[" I don't know why you all seem to think there's something magical about the VLab environment. It just gives you a \"virtual screen\" which is equivalent to sitting on a CSE workstation and doing things. What kind of error does the download page give? And how are you trying to access it? ",[" I do not know what is happening here. I just clicked on the files.tar icon on the cs1521 page ",[" This is a browser problem rather than a VLab problem. An easy way to get the exam.tar file would be to run the command: cp ~cs1521/web/18s2/exams/17s2final/files/exam.tar . Or, even better, make a directory where you want to work on the exam, change into that directory, and then run the command: tar xf ~cs1521/web/18s2/exams/17s2final/files/exam.tar and it will put all of the relevant files in your directory. ",[" Thank you so much Dr. Shepherd! "]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"flip digits","salience":0.5831098556518555},{"name":"sample exam","salience":0.21555322408676147},{"name":"solution","salience":0.10534399002790451},{"name":"number","salience":0.05989145115017891},{"name":"calculation","salience":0.03610147163271904}],"question":" For q4(A i) in 2017 sample exam, 00000000000000000000000000101010 flip digits-&gt; 11111111 11111111 11111111 11010101 add 1-&gt; 11111111 11111111 11111111 11010110 which is a huge number instead of 42 in the solution. What is wrong with my calculation? Thank you. ","answers":[" You misread the question. What I wanted was for you interpret the bit-string as a number X in twos-complement format. What you've done is negate the number and given -X. I was asking you tell me what X was. ",[" Hi, In the 2017 sample exam, q6D. Write a recursive function to free the memory associated with a list (i.e. free all of the Node s). Use the following function header: void freeNodes(Node *L) { ... The solution is void freeNodes(Node *L) { if (L != NULL) { freeNodes(L-&gt;next); free(L); } } I don't quite understand how it is recursive. Isn't it just freeing L and L-&gt;next? What if there exists L-&gt;next-&gt;next? Thanks ",[" It's recursive because it calls itself, as long as the list isn't empty (which happens when the recursion winds its way to the end of the list). COMP1521 doesn't cover recursion (much) or linked lists but COMP1511 does, AFAIK. "]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"octal","salience":0.42624929547309875},{"name":"answer","salience":0.12853506207466125},{"name":"answer","salience":0.08330389857292175},{"name":"answers","salience":0.07334735989570618},{"name":"question","salience":0.06702771037817001},{"name":"digit","salience":0.05973450466990471},{"name":"bits","salience":0.04679759591817856},{"name":"question7 b","salience":0.03249092772603035},{"name":"thanks","salience":0.028838898986577988},{"name":"advance","salience":0.028838898986577988},{"name":"bits","salience":0.024835843592882156}],"question":" For 2017 sample q6, Converting 100 in decimal to octal. Why answer is 0144 rather than 144 (also for all other answers in this question, there are all one 0 in the left most digit)? And for question7 B, why the answer could be 0? Isn't like lb loads bits from lower to higher up to 8 bits so that 1001 1010 can only be loaded? Thanks in advance! ","answers":[" 0144 is to make the point that it's octal, since a leading-0 is how you indicate octal in C On some architectures it could be zero. Of course, we're dealing with MIPS and so it can't. I assume that you wrote a small MIPS program to check. "," Got the idea of 0, for signed octal. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"solutions","salience":1}],"question":" are solutions for this going to be released? ","answers":[" They're now there ... follow the Solutions link "," Only after you've attempted the questions. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"output","salience":0.22755862772464752},{"name":"rmm0d function","salience":0.16451075673103333},{"name":"exam1","salience":0.12487263977527618},{"name":"answer","salience":0.04950234293937683},{"name":"tl","salience":0.049115173518657684},{"name":"quirk","salience":0.047960225492715836},{"name":"output","salience":0.03268345072865486},{"name":"reason","salience":0.02636854350566864},{"name":"files","salience":0.026309702545404434},{"name":"machines","salience":0.024101080372929573},{"name":"re-start","salience":0.020652733743190765},{"name":"bug","salience":0.018466778099536896},{"name":"default","salience":0.018146775662899017},{"name":"home","salience":0.018146775662899017},{"name":"cs1521","salience":0.018146775662899017},{"name":"dr","salience":0.015258990228176117},{"name":"bug","salience":0.014446022920310497},{"name":"cse","salience":0.014264839701354504},{"name":"ssh","salience":0.014264839701354504},{"name":"anyone","salience":0.014103381894528866},{"name":"code","salience":0.012691252864897251},{"name":"system","salience":0.012691252864897251},{"name":"bin path","salience":0.01073538325726986},{"name":"re-start q1","salience":0.009068996645510197},{"name":"spec","salience":0.007966333068907261},{"name":"command","salience":0.007966333068907261}],"question":" Hi, I've completed Exam1 q1. The rmm0d function is running correctly (I think) however there seems to be a quirk in the output. I get the correct answer however the output differs to the expected output. This happens in all *.cmp. Does anyone know the reason why this would occur? I'm running exe arrays.s to create the files. I'm doing this while SSH'd into the CSE machines. I've tried to use the `re-start q1` command as suggested in the spec however I don't think `re-start` exists in the default or /home/cs1521/bin PATH anymore. TL;DR Is this a bug in my code or a bug in the system? ","answers":[" Yes. The expected output contains a line (the \"Loaded\" one) which is filtered out of your output by check . Feel free to change the expected output files and remove the \"Loaded\" lines if you want the satisfaction of seeing \"Test X Passed\". "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"exam spec front sheet","salience":0.4907684624195099},{"name":"calculator apps","salience":0.2106301486492157},{"name":"ones","salience":0.1514178067445755},{"name":"gnome-calculator","salience":0.1471835821866989}],"question":" The exam spec front sheet says that calculator apps are available, do you know which ones exactly I can use (or more specifically will gnome-calculator be available)? ","answers":[" xcalc and bc "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"script","salience":0.20550602674484253},{"name":"exe","salience":0.18702813982963562},{"name":"check","salience":0.18483322858810425},{"name":"answer","salience":0.17217282950878143},{"name":"17s2 exam","salience":0.17217282950878143},{"name":"chmod 755","salience":0.07828693836927414}],"question":" I don't understand how could i install the script of check and exe to verify my answer of 17s2 exam, should I use \"chmod 755\" or what? ","answers":[" That would certainly help. And you could always run them as \"sh check\" or \"sh exe\" if you copy the scripts into the directory where you're working. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"message","salience":0.3055666387081146},{"name":"tests","salience":0.2886413037776947},{"name":"function","salience":0.2558741867542267},{"name":"sth","salience":0.07618153095245361},{"name":"pointer","salience":0.045211970806121826},{"name":"getstudents","salience":0.0285243671387434}],"question":" For practical exam2 q2, the tests/8.exp, should it print a message about null (empty atm)? In main function, it seems if getStudents() return a null pointer, it print sth. ","answers":[]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"files","salience":0.7614729404449463},{"name":"vlab","salience":0.23852704465389252}],"question":" How to install these files into vlab? ","answers":[" Which files specifically? "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"sample exams"},{"name":"check","salience":0.5817844867706299},{"name":"program","salience":0.2559589147567749},{"name":"way","salience":0.16225659847259521}],"question":" can't use check, is there any other way to check program? ","answers":[" Run the tests by hand (look at the tests/*.sh files). Compare your output against the tests/*.exp (or whatever they're called) files. In other words, look in the tests/ directory and work it out from there. "]}]}